<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DR &amp; Migration on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/</link><description>Recent content in DR &amp; Migration on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Planning and Preparation</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/planning/</guid><description>Planning and Preparation # Everything you need to know before deploying VMware Cloud Director Availability.
Hardware Requirements # Appliance Type Description and Services Hardware Requirements Cloud Replication Management Appliance A dedicated appliance, that runs the following VMware Cloud Director Availability services: * Manager Service * Cloud Service with embedded VMware Cloud Director Availability Tenant Portal - 2 vCPUs - 4 GB RAM</description></item><item><title>Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/design/</guid><description>Design # Architecture # The following diagram shows the network flow between the VMware Cloud Director Availability components and the other infrastructure components part of the replication process.
Other Components # Platform Services Controller # All the VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances need to be configured with a Lookup Service for two purposes:
Service authentication and resource discovery – the Replicator and Management appliances require registration with a Lookup Service to authenticate to the resource vCenters and discover resources which is required for operations from the VMware Cloud Director Availability workflow.</description></item><item><title>Implementation</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/implementation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/implementation/</guid><description>Implementation # Welcome!</description></item><item><title>Operations</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/operations/</guid><description>Operations # VMware Cloud Director Availability Multi-NIC Configuration # Below you can find the full instructions how to properly configure multiple network interfaces on each of the VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances - Cloud Replications Management, Cloud Replicator and Cloud Tunnel.
Multi-NIC Configuration Instructions
VMware Cloud Director Availability Certificate Management # Below you can find the full instructions how to maintain the VMware Cloud Director Availability certificates.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Director Availability Certificate Management</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/certificate-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/certificate-management/</guid><description>VMware Cloud Director Availability Certificate Management # The SSL certificates are essential for establishing a trusted connection between the different VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances and their proper service.
Each of them comes with their unique self-signed SSL certificate during the deployment. But still, these certificates need to be replaced when they expire, or if the providers prefer to use CA-signed ones to make sure there will be no browser warnings, for example.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Director Availability Multi-NIC Configuration</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/multi-nic-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/multi-nic-config/</guid><description>VMware Cloud Director Availability Multi-NIC Configuration # Overview # Placing the VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances in different networks is something common for Service Providers. This leads to the need to use multiple network interfaces to support that scenario and guarantee the product will continue operating as per design.
There are a few main reasons that lead to this design:
Bypass a router
Port forwarding is not possible</description></item></channel></rss>