<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DR and Migration on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/</link><description>Recent content in DR and Migration on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Add the VMware Cloud Director Availability Instance to Usage Meter</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/attach-um-to-vcda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/attach-um-to-vcda/</guid><description>Add the VMware Cloud Director Availability Instance to Usage Meter # Prerequisites # vCloud Usage Meter can connect to VMware Cloud Director Availability. You have the root credentials for the VMware Cloud Director Availability appliance. The VMware Cloud Director Availability certificate is FIPS compliant. Procedure # In the main menu bar of the vCloud Usage Meter Web interface, click Products. In the left navigation pane, click VMware Cloud Director Availability.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Director Availability Metering</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/cloud-director-availability-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/cloud-director-availability-metering/</guid><description>Cloud Director Availability Metering # Usage Meter collects the number of all replications (migrations and protections) configured in VMware Cloud Director Availability during the month. The collection is performed on an hourly basis. Replications for both powered-on and powered-off VMs are counted. At the end of the month, the report shows the number of all the unique migrated VMs and all the unique protected VMs.
Prerequisites # vCloud Usage Meter can connect to VMware Cloud Director Availability.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Logical Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/logical-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/logical-design/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Logical Design #</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Network Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/network-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/network-design/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Network Design #</description></item><item><title>Deployment of the VMware Cloud Director Availability Appliances</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/deploy-vcda-appliances/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/deploy-vcda-appliances/</guid><description>Deployment of the VMware Cloud Director Availability Appliances # Deployment Steps # The deployment of the VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances in the vCenter Server is done by following these steps:
In the vCenter UI click on Deploy OVF Template&amp;hellip;
Select the VMware Cloud Director Availability OVF template.
Name the virtual machine.
Select a destination compute resource.
Review the virtual machine details.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Backup and Restore</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/backup-restore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/backup-restore/</guid><description>DR and Migration Backup and Restore # You can generate a new backup for each VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances in their own UI or do it directly from the Cloud Replication Manager appliance, where backups for all appliances will be generated.
The backup archive contains the following information from each appliance in the cloud site:
Configuration files Public certificate Keystore Database dump The backup does not contain:</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Certificate Management</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/cert-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/cert-management/</guid><description>DR and Migration Certificate Management # The SSL certificates are essential for establishing a trusted connection between the different VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances and their proper service.
Each of them comes with their unique self-signed SSL certificate during the deployment. But still, these certificates need to be replaced when they expire, or if the providers prefer to use CA-signed ones to make sure there will be no browser warnings, for example.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Deployment Specification</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/deployment-spec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/deployment-spec/</guid><description>DR and Migration Deployment Specification # The deployment specification covers the design decisions regarding the design and sizing of the VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances.
Deployment Model # You consider the deployment model according to the design objectives and scale of your DR and migration services.
A VMware Cloud Director Availability instance is required in each VMware Cloud Foundation instance that is intended to be utilized for the DR and migration services offered to tenants.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/design/</guid><description>DR and Migration Design # The DR and Migration validated solution has objectives to deliver prescriptive content about the solution so that it is fast to deploy and is suitable for use in production environments.
Objective Description Main objective Enable DR and migration services for the VMware Cloud Director Organizations on VMware Cloud Foundation. VMware Cloud Foundation architecture support vSAN ReadyNodes</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Detailed Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/detailed-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/detailed-design/</guid><description>DR and Migration Detailed Design # The {VVS for CP Title} validated solution uses {VVS Product} deployed on top of а VMware Cloud Foundation VI workload domain to &amp;hellip;
Logical Design for {VVS for CP Title} # The logical design consists of multiple elements that enable you to deploy and manage infrastructure used to {VVS Product Purpose}. [Read more]
Deployment Specification for VMware Cloud Director Availability # The deployment specification covers the design decisions regarding the design and sizing of the VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Implementation</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/implementation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/implementation/</guid><description>Implementing DR and Migration validated solution includes configuring VMware Cloud Director Availability.
To implement and configure VMware Cloud Director Availability, you can use the user interface of each component in the solution.
This guidance provides a prescriptive path for deploying VMware Cloud Director Availability in a management and/or VI workload domain.
Prerequisites # Here is a high-level list of the requirements to deploy VMware Cloud Director Availability. For more details, please refer to the official documentation.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Information Security and Access</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/info-sec-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/info-sec-access/</guid><description>DR and Migration Information Security and Access # Identity Management Design # Each VMware Cloud Director Availability appliance has just a single system administrator user (root). Its password is configured during the appliance deployment and must be changed during the initial setup wizard or at the first login to this appliance.
Additionally, a VMware Cloud Director service account with system administrator privileges needs to be created for the VMware Cloud Director Availability registration to the VMware Cloud Director instance.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Lifecycle Management</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/lifecycle-mgmt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/lifecycle-mgmt/</guid><description>DR and Migration Lifecycle Management # The lifecycle management of VMware Cloud Director Availability is provided using the native tools in each of the appliances. All deployment, patching, and upgrade operations are performed manually by the system administrator without or with minimal native automation.
Most of the operations (deployment, upgrades) can be performed through the graphical user interface of VMware Cloud Director Availability while some of them are also available through the command-line.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Metering</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/metering/</guid><description>DR and Migration Metering # How to start metering your DR and Migration products with Usage Meter # The following information helps you understand how Usage Meter detects and meters the usage of the listed VMware products and their features.
It also provides insight into how the reported usage data is calculated and appears in the Usage Insight reports.
Metering DR and Migration Products # Cloud Director Availability</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Operations</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/operations/</guid><description>DR and Migration Operations # After you complete the implementation of VMware Cloud Director Availability, you can perform common operations on the environment related to maintaining the proper functionality of the DR and Migration services.
For operational guidance on the components that are deployed automatically in VMware Cloud Foundation or complement the basic VMware Cloud Foundation configuration, see the VMware Cloud Foundation Operations and Administration Guide in the VMware Cloud Foundation documentation.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Password Management</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/pwd-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/pwd-management/</guid><description>DR and Migration Password Management # VMware Cloud Director Availability doesn&amp;rsquo;t have its users and permissions system but utilizes the organization structure and authentication mechanisms of VMware Cloud Director.
As a result, there is only one local user for each appliance - the system administrator user (root).
VMware Cloud Director Availability uses the root user account for access to both the virtual appliance console and the management interface. The initial deployment of each VMware Cloud Director Availability appliance sets up this account.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Personas</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/personas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/personas/</guid><description>DR and Migration Personas # In the VMware Cloud Director Availability terminology, there are two types of personas:
Service providers manage VMware Cloud Director Availability objects and the local VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances after authenticating as VMware Cloud Director System Administrator users. By default, the System Administrator role has all VMware Cloud Director rights. Users belonging to that role can manage any local and monitor any remote VMware Cloud Director Availability inventory object.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Planning and Preparation</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/planning/</guid><description>DR and Migration Planning and Preparation # Before you start implementing the components of the DR and Migration solution, you must set up an environment that has a specific compute, storage, and network configuration, and that provides external services to the components of the solution.
Use the VMware Cloud Foundation Planning and Preparation Workbook to capture environment specific input values that are required during the implementation.
Carefully review the VMware Cloud Foundation Planning and Preparation Workbook before implementation to avoid costly rework and delays.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Shutdown and Startup</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/shutdown-startup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/shutdown-startup/</guid><description>DR and Migration Shutdown and Startup # Start/Stop/Status # To start, restart, stop or see the status of each of the VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances, you need to establish an SSH session to the respective appliance and run the following command:
systemctl {start|restart|stop|status} &amp;lt;Service_System_Unit&amp;gt; The different services and their system units can be found in the table below.
Service Name System Unit VMware Cloud on AWS Data Engine Service h4dm Replicator Service replicator Manager Service manager Cloud Service cloud Tunnel Service tunnel vSphere Replication Server hbrsrv Lightweight Delta Protocol Service lwdproxy PostgreSQL database server h4postgresql Restart through the UI # As part of the troubleshooting, you can restart all VMware Cloud Director Availability services in the appliance from the System health page.</description></item><item><title>DR and Migration Verification</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/verification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/verification/</guid><description>DR and Migration Verification # The VMware Cloud Director Availability System Health page indicates the overall status of the service and appliances. It is highly recommended to verify the status after the initial setup or any maintenance operations such as an upgrade, certificate changes, password changes or other.
Service status # Verify the connectivity statuses in the local cloud site to the following infrastructure services.
Connectivity to the vCenter Server Lookup service.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up VMware Cloud Director Availability</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/setup-vcda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/setup-vcda/</guid><description>Setting Up VMware Cloud Director Availability # Port mapping # The communication between the different appliances occurs at the following ports as shown on the diagram.
Requirements # Here is a high-level list of the requirements to deploy VMware Cloud Director Availability. For more details, please refer to the official documentation.
DNS and NTP server
SSO Lookup Service Address
Routing and Firewall Ports in place</description></item><item><title>Setting Up VMware Cloud Director Availability at a VMC on AWS SDDC</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/vcda-vmc-on-aws-sddc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/vcda-vmc-on-aws-sddc/</guid><description>Setting Up VMware Cloud Director Availability at a VMC on AWS SDDC # Prerequisites # To be able to successfully deploy and run VMware Cloud Director Availability in your VMC on AWS environment, you will need to make sure the following requirements are met:
Have a properly deployed Software-Defined Data Center (SDDC). Have a VMware Cloud Director deployed at VMC on AWS (Cloud Director service) that is linked to the SDDC.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Director Availability Appliances Initial Configuration</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/vcda-initial-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/vcda-initial-config/</guid><description>VMware Cloud Director Availability Appliances Initial Configuration # Login to the appliance at the following URL: https://&amp;lt;Cloud-Replication-Management-Appliance-URL&amp;gt;/admin.
Enter the password defined during the deployment process.
Since it is the first login to the system, you will be prompted to change the password.
Click Run Initial Setup Wizard. Note that all the steps are mandatory, and you cannot skip any of them.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Director Availability Certificate Management</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/vcda-gcve-sddc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/vcda-gcve-sddc/</guid><description>Setting Up VMware Cloud Director Availability at a GCVE SDDC # User Permissions for Google Cloud VMware Engine # The default vSphere administrative user that comes with Google Cloud VMware Engine is CloudOwner@gve.local. Despite its administrative rights, the CloudOwner user misses some privileges (like Host.Config.Connection, for example) for the VMware Cloud Director Availability Classic data engine to operate properly. Even the temporary elevation of the CloudOwner privileges (link) does not help to perform a successful replication.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Director Availability Multi-NIC Configuration</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/multi-nic-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/dr-migration/multi-nic-config/</guid><description>VMware Cloud Director Availability Multi-NIC Configuration # Overview # Placing the VMware Cloud Director Availability appliances in different networks is something common for Service Providers. This leads to the need to use multiple network interfaces to support that scenario and guarantee the product will continue operating as per design.
There are a few main reasons that lead to this design:
Bypass a router
Port forwarding is not possible</description></item></channel></rss>