<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Infrastructure on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Infrastructure on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Load Balancing for Cloud Infrastructure</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-lb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-lb/</guid><description>Advanced Load Balancing for Cloud Infrastructure # After you implement the Cloud Infrastructure validated solution, you can enable load balancing services for VMware Cloud Director tenants by integrating it with the Advanced Load Balancing services for the VI Workload Domain in your VMware Cloud Foundation environment.
For validated load balancing solutions, see Advanced Load Balancing Validated Solutions.[link]
Integration with NSX Advanced Load Balancer # If your environment is running NSX Advanced Load Balancer, you can connect VMware Cloud Director to the Advanced Load Balancing service.</description></item><item><title>Appendix for Cloud Infrastructure</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/appendix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/appendix/</guid><description>Appendix for Cloud Infrastructure # The Scale and Performance Guidelines documents the validation of the Cloud Infrastructure solution and provides scale and performance indicators for similarly sized deployments.
Scale and Performance Guidelines #</description></item><item><title>Cloud Director Availability Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cloud-director-availability-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cloud-director-availability-metering/</guid><description>Cloud Director Availability Metering and Reporting # vCloud Usage Meter 4.6 detects configured for protection or migration of virtual machines using VMware Cloud Director Availability, where the source or destination is a replication-enabled VMware Cloud Director or a dedicated VMware vSphere cloud.
Configuration # VMware Cloud Director Availability Management Appliance or vCenter Replication Management Appliance instance must be registered with Usage Meter by providing the appliance IP address, or hostname and root credentials.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Director Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cloud-director-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cloud-director-metering/</guid><description>Cloud Director Metering and Reporting # Configuration # Usage meter collects product usage information from all VMware Cloud Director endpoints that are registered with Usage Meter. The Usage Meter administrator must configure the endpoint and credentials through the Usage Meter web application.
Feature Detection # Usage Meter calculates an Average Capped Billed vRAM (GB) value for all virtual machines managed by Cloud Director. Refer to the vCenter Server section for a detailed description of the Average Capped Billed vRAM formula.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Certificate Management</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cert-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cert-management/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Certificate Management # Starting with VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager 1.4, you can use the UI to manage the product certificates.
With VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager, you can specify the following VMware Cloud Director certificates. Product certificates can be viewed, downloaded and replaced using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager.
Manage VMware Cloud Director certificates # Procedure # To access the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager UI, navigate to https://vcplcmhost-name and login as vcplcm.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Deployment Specification</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/deployment-spec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/deployment-spec/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Deployment Specification # Component Version Size Resources Optional Components that can be deployed by VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager VMware Cloud Director 10.5 Virtual appliance Extra Large Configuration 1 Primary (Large) 2 Standby cells (Large) 2 Application Cells (Large) Each Primary Cell RAM: 32 GB CPU: 24 Storage: 202 GB (increased root partition to 50 GB for logs, increased PostgreSQL database disk to 150 GB) Each Standby Cell RAM: 32 GB CPU: 24 Storage: 202 GB (increased root partition to 50 GB for logs, increased PostgreSQL database disk to 150 GB) Each Application Cell RAM: 8 GB CPU: 8 Storage: 132 GB (increased root partition to 50 GB for logs) • Usage Meter</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Design Decisions</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/design-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/design-decisions/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Design Decisions # NOTE: For each section below, use either a dedicated decision table for each component in the VVS or a single table with decisions for all components depending on the number of decisions listed. # Deployment Model for Cloud Infrastructure # Design Decisions for deploying VMware Cloud Director # Design ID Design Decision Design Justification Design Implication VCPLCM-VCD-001 Use VCD appliances instead of installing VCD binaries on Linux VMs.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Design Objectives</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/design/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Design Objectives # The deployment of VMware Cloud Director on VMware Cloud Foundation using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager validated solution has objectives to deliver prescriptive content about the solution so that it is fast to deploy and is suitable for use in production environments.
Objective Description Main Objective Provide enterprise-grade validated VMware Cloud Director infrastructure on VMware Cloud Foundation deployed by VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager VMware Cloud Foundation Architecture Support vSAN Ready Nodes Standard</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Detailed Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/detailed-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/detailed-design/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Detailed Design # The Cloud Infrastructure validated solution uses VMware Cloud Director, Usage Meter, vRealize Operations Manager Tenant App, RabbitMQ and VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager deployed on top of а VMware Cloud Foundation VI workload domain to build an hybrid cloud environment.
Logical Design for Cloud Infrastructure # The logical design consists of multiple elements that enable you to deploy and manage infrastructure used for setting up a robust Cloud Infrastructure based on VMware Cloud Director.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Implementation</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/implementation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/implementation/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Implementation # Implementing VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager validated solution includes deployment of Appliance and setting up the product binary.
To deploy and configure VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager, please follow VMware Documentation
This guidance provides a prescriptive path for deploying VMware Cloud Director, vRealize Operations Manager Tenant App, Usage Meter and RabbitMQ using API feature of VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager in a management domain of VMware Cloud Foundation .</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Information Security and Access</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/info-sec-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/info-sec-access/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Information Security and Access #</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Lifecycle Management</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/lifecycle-mgmt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/lifecycle-mgmt/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Lifecycle Management # Deployment, Upgrades, and day-2 Operations of products like VMware Cloud Director, Usage Meter, Chargeback and RabbitMQ will be performed by VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Management (VCPLCM).
Below architecturural diagram explains the task flow and above mentioned features of VCPLCM.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Logical Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/logical-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/logical-design/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Logical Design # The logical design provides a high-level overview of the solution design.
VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager simplifies the operational experience by providing a comprehensive solution to deploy, upgrade, configure, and manage the VMware Cloud Provider Program products.
The Cloud Infrastucture stack is comprised of the following components:
VMware VMware Cloud Director
VMware VMware Cloud Director is VMware’s flagship cloud services platform for Cloud Providers. It is a pervasive cloud infrastructure control plane for cloud providers’ service-delivery needs, and the management entity for a global VMware cloud estate.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Metering</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/metering/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Metering # vCloud Usage Meter is a virtual appliance for tracking the usage of the VMware products part of the VMware Cloud Provider Program that are deployed on-prem and paid based on pay-as-you-grow model.
The Usage Meter appliance is installed on-prem through vSphere and connects to the metered products through their IPs and the users who are able to connect to them. After the successful connection to the metered products is established, the collection of usage data starts.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Network Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/network-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/network-design/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Network Design # Network Design of Management Cluster for VMware Cloud Foundation # The following picture shows the network design for all the components in the Cloud Infrastructure and how they are managed using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecyclle Manager
Reg.Mgmt and X.Reg.Mgmt
These are overlay Segments
Existing Reg. Mgmt is used for a secondary interface for VCD cells, vSAN FS, Usage meter, vRealize Operations</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Operations</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/operations/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Operations # After you complete the implementation of the Cloud Infrastructure, you perform common operations on the environment, such as &amp;hellip;
For operational guidance on the components that are deployed automatically in VMware Cloud Foundation or complement the basic VMware Cloud Foundation configuration, see the VMware Cloud Foundation Operations and Administration Guide in the VMware Cloud Foundation documentation.
Personas in Cloud Infrastructure # Personas describe types of system users, aligned with real people and their functions within the organization.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Password Management</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/pwd-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/pwd-management/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Password Management #</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Personas</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/personas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/personas/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Personas # In the Overall Cloud Infrastructure, there are two types of personas:
Service providers : Service providers manage VMware Cloud Foundation objects and the product appliances like Usage Meter, Chargeback and RabbitMQ .Scervice providers will have System Admin rights. By default, the System Administrator role has all VMware Cloud Director rights. Users belonging to that role can manage any inventory object. Along with cplcm user, Service providers will have root priviledges to VMware Cloud provider Lifecycle manager.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Planning and Preparation</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/planning/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Planning and Preparation # Before you start implementing the components of the Cloud Infrastructure solution, you must set up an environment that has a specific compute, storage, and network configuration, and that provides external services to the components of the solution.
Use the VMware Cloud Foundation Planning and Preparation Workbook to capture environment specific input values that are required during the implementation.
Carefully review the VMware Cloud Foundation Planning and Preparation Workbook before implementation to avoid costly rework and delays.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Shutdown and Startup</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/shutdown-startup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/shutdown-startup/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Shutdown and Startup #</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Verification</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/verification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/verification/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Verification # Cloud Infrastructure deployment Verification # After the initial deployment of the products, refer the below options to check system health It is highly recommended to verify the status after the initial setup or any maintenance operations such as an upgrade, certificate changes, password changes or other.
VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager: # Service status : # Verify the connectivity statuses of the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle manager to the infrastructure services.</description></item><item><title>Horizon DaaS Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/horizon-daas-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/horizon-daas-metering/</guid><description>Horizon DaaS Metering and Reporting # Product Detection # For setting up VMware Horizon DaaS usage collection, for every Horizon DaaS deployment (each unique Horizon DaaS Service Provider implementation), the provider needs to register it in the Usage Meter 4.5.0.1 web application.
To set up the Horizon Desktop as a Service usage collection, the provider selects Horizon Desktop as Service in the Usage Meter web application, adds a new entry, and then enters the Horizon DaaS appliance IP address or hostname, port, username, password, and active directory domain.</description></item><item><title>Horizon Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/horizon-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/horizon-metering/</guid><description>Horizon Metering and Reporting # Product Detection # Horizon is added for metering in Usage Meter 4.5.0.1. The provider needs to enter the endpoint IP address or hostname, user and password, and the domain to which Horizon belongs. After the product certificate is accepted in the Usage Meter web application and the connection to Horizon is successful, the data collection starts.
Metering # Usage Meter 4.5.0.1 collects data for the number of concurrent connections from the Horizon Connection Server and the license with which the concurrent connections are associated.</description></item><item><title>LifeCycle Management for Cloud Infrastructure</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-lifecycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-lifecycle/</guid><description>LifeCycle Management for Cloud Infrastructure # After you implement VMware Cloud Director, Usage Meter, RabbitMQ and chargeback , lifecycle management for the Cloud Infrastructure components is managed by VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager.
For information on the impact of performing lifecycle management of the products in this validated solution on VMware Cloud Foundation and other validated solutions that might be deployed in your environment, see VMware Knowledge Base Article KBxxxxx.</description></item><item><title>Load Balancing as a Service in VMware Cloud Director</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-lb-proceedure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-lb-proceedure/</guid><description>Proceedure to Enable Load Balancing as a Service in VMware Cloud Director # VMware Cloud Director Service Admin Portal # The first step is to register the controller cluster with VMware Cloud Director.
To provide virtual service management capabilities to your tenants:
Register your Avi Controller instances with your VMware Cloud Director instance. Register your NSX-T Cloud instances with VMware Cloud Director. Import all the relevant service engine groups to your VMware Cloud Director deployment.</description></item><item><title>Logging for Cloud Infrastructure</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-logging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-logging/</guid><description>Logging for Cloud Infrastructure # After you implement the {VVS for CP Title} validated solution, monitor the components that are newly added to or reconfigured in your VMware Cloud Foundation environment.
For validated monitoring solutions, see VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solutions.[link]
Integration with vRealize Log Insight # If your environment is running vRealize Log Insight, you can connect vRealize Log Insight to the {VVS for CP Title} components.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring and Alerting for Cloud Infrastructure</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-monitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop-monitor/</guid><description>Monitoring and Alerting for Cloud Infrastructure # After you implement the {VVS for CP Title} validated solution, monitor the components that are newly added to or reconfigured in your VMware Cloud Foundation environment.
For validated monitoring solutions, see VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solutions.[link]
Integration with vRealize Operations Manager # If your environment is running vRealize Operations Manager, you can connect vRealize Operations Manager to the {VVS for CP Title} components.</description></item><item><title>NSX Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/nsx-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/nsx-metering/</guid><description>NSX Metering and Reporting # Usage Meter 4.5.0.1 can detect specific NSX features available to Virtual Machines, which determines the NSX edition billed to a VM.
Usage Meter 4.5.0.1 tracks NSX usage by Virtual Machine based on the networking services available to the Virtual Machine.
Configuration # The Usage Meter administrator must configure the NSX Manager endpoint and credentials using the Usage Meter web application. There is one NSX Manager for each vCenter server instance utilizing NSX.</description></item><item><title>RabbitMQ Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/rabbit-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/rabbit-design/</guid><description>RabbitMQ Design # Detailed design information for RabbitMQ goes here.
Deployment model Design decisions Sizing Others</description></item><item><title>Scale and Performance Guidelines</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/scale-performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/scale-performance/</guid><description>Scale and Performance Guidelines #</description></item><item><title>Solution Interoperability of Cloud Infrastructure</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/solution-interop/</guid><description>Solution Interoperability of Cloud Infrastructure # Integrate the Cloud Infrastructure validated solution with components added to your VMware Cloud Foundation environment by other validated solutions for operations management and business continuity. You can use such validated solutions for logging, backup and restore, disaster recovery, and life cycle management with certain considerations.
This validated solution includes guidance only for implementing intelligent operations management. Performing all deployments and configurations for operations management and business continuity are out of scope.</description></item><item><title>SRM Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/srm-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/srm-metering/</guid><description>SRM Metering and Reporting # VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM) is a disaster recovery solution that provides automated orchestration and non-disruptive testing of centralized recovery plans for all virtualized applications. It allows service providers to offer reliable, automated protection for workloads hosted on their own cloud infrastructure and being replicated to another cloud destination (DR of the cloud) or workloads running on customer premises and being replicated to the cloud infrastructure (DR to the Cloud).</description></item><item><title>Tanzu Kubernetes Grid Multi-Cloud Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/tkgm-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/tkgm-metering/</guid><description>Tanzu Kubernetes Grid Multi-cloud (TKGm) Metering and Reporting # Configuration # To start metering Tanzu Kubernetes Grid Multi-cloud, you need to provide the TKGm management cluster IP address or hostname, bearer token that you will use to authenticate with the cluster, the Tanzu edition, and metric that will be used to calculate your TKGm consumption. Metering For each TKGm management cluster added for metering to Usage Meter 4.6, the latter will get information about the cluster and its workload clusters.</description></item><item><title>Tanzu Kubernetes Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/tkgs-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/tkgs-metering/</guid><description>Tanzu Kubernetes Metering and Reporting # Configuration # Tanzu is automatically detected if the Usage Meter administrator configures the endpoint and credentials for each vCenter to be metered using the Usage Meter web application. The Usage Meter administrator can choose to either meter Tanzu as a vRAM or CPU cores metric by selecting the respective option from the &amp;ldquo;If Tanzu is detected, choose the metric to report:&amp;rdquo; drop-down list.</description></item><item><title>vCenter Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcenter-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcenter-metering/</guid><description>vCenter Server Metering and Reporting # Usage Meter collects product usage information from all vCenter servers that are registered with Usage Meter.
Note: Usage Meter does not traverse Enhanced Linked Mode, and it requires registering all vCenter servers, part of this mode, to meter their usage data.
Note: VMware Cloud Provider Program partners should utilize VCPP licenses for all servers used in the service delivery path or administration control plane.</description></item><item><title>VMware Aria Automation 7.x Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vra7x-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vra7x-metering/</guid><description>VMware Aria Automation 7.x Metering and Reporting # VMware Aria Automation 7.x is available to service providers in two editions:
VMware Aria Automation Advanced VMware Aria Automation Enterprise Product Detection # The cloud provider must register the VMware Aria Automation instance in the Usage Meter web application. Then the cloud provider must enter the Cafe and IaaS hostname, port, username, and password. A validation of the user credentials is performed and if correct, the data collection starts.</description></item><item><title>VMware Aria Automation 8.x Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vra8x-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vra8x-metering/</guid><description>VMware Aria Automation 8.x Metering and Reporting # The VMware Aria Automation 8.x is automatically registered as part of VMware Aria Suite Lifecycle Manager registration in Usage Meter 4.6.
Pre-requisites # To meter successfully VMware Aria Automation 8.X, ensure the following prerequisites have been met. • Verify that the VMware Aria Automation 8.x is imported or deployed in a VMware Aria Suite Lifecycle Manager environment. • Verify that the VMware Aria Automation 8.</description></item><item><title>VMware Aria Operations for Networks Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vrni-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vrni-metering/</guid><description>VMware Aria Operations for Networks Metering and Reporting # VMware VMware Aria Operations for Networks is available to service providers in two editions:
VMware Aria Operations for Networks Advanced VMware Aria Operations for Networks Enterprise Metering # VMware Aria Operations for Networks is reported depending on the provider’s preference. The following are the available reporting options for VMware Aria Operations for Networks:
Standalone – When VMware Aria Operations for Networks is reported as a standalone product, then the metering is per VM or OSI per Month.</description></item><item><title>VMware Aria Operations Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vrops-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vrops-metering/</guid><description>VMware Aria Operations Metering and Reporting # Usage Meter supports several VMware Aria Operations (vROps) configurations:
A Service Provider managed VMware Aria Operations server monitoring a single tenant. A Service Provider hosted VMware Aria Operations server for multiple tenants. A Service Provider hosted VMware Aria Operations server that manages VMs hosted by SP or hosted on customer’s premises. A VMware Aria Operations server configured with multiple vCenter servers. Configuration # VMware Aria Operations in Usage Meter 4.</description></item><item><title>VMware Chargeback (formerly vRealize Operations Tenant App) Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/ta-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/ta-design/</guid><description>VMware Chargeback (formerly vRealize Operations Tenant App) Design # VMware supports thousands of partners to host and sell clouds built on VMware technology using vCenter and Cloud Director (VCD). While vCenter provides the core of virtualization, Cloud Director provides needed constructs for segmenting the virtual infrastructure appropriately and offering it as a service to tenants of these partners.
As can be imagined, there are several variants of infrastructure that can be sold by these partners such as “Pay as you go”, “Raw capacity” aka “Allocation based”, “Raw capacity with minimum guarantee” aka “Reservation based”, “Flex” i.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation Metering and Reporting</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcf-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcf-metering/</guid><description>VMware Cloud Foundation Metering and Reporting # Configuration # The Usage Meter administrator configures a vCenter and selects any of the VCF license editions to enable VCF for metering. Metering Time-based average of host CPU core count aggregated by the following different VCF editions:
VMware Cloud Foundation for Cloud Providers Standard VMware Cloud Foundation for Cloud Providers Advanced VMware Cloud Foundation for Cloud Providers Enterprise VMware Cloud Foundation for Cloud Providers Standard without vSAN VMware Cloud Foundation for Cloud Providers Advanced without vSAN VMware Cloud Foundation for Cloud Providers Enterprise without vSAN Time-based average capped billed vRAM GB per VM VCF edition:</description></item><item><title>VMware vCloud Usage Meter Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/um-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/um-design/</guid><description>VMware vCloud Usage Meter Design # Detailed design information for Usage Meter goes here.
Deployment model # vCloud Usage Meter is deployed as an OVA file through vSphere. It must be registered with a VCPP contract (Rental or Sovereign Cloud) to complete its configuration. 1 vCloud Usage Meter can be registered with only 1 VCPP contract. A single VCPP contract can have many registered vCloud Usage Meters. Usage Meter can also be registered with a provider org&amp;rsquo;s site.</description></item><item><title>vSAN Metering and Reporing</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vsan-metering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vsan-metering/</guid><description>vSAN Metering and Reporting # vSAN is activated at a host-cluster level either while creating new clusters or updating existing host clusters. vSAN aggregates all local storage devices across all hosts in the vSAN cluster into a single datastore. More storage devices or hosts can be added to the cluster to expand its datastore capacity. If a host contributes to the vSAN datastore, it must provide at least one device for flash cache and another for persistent storage.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-appliance-deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-appliance-deployment/</guid><description># Deploy VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager On VMware Cloud Foundation # # Deploy VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager on VMware Cloud Foundation for automated deployment of products like VMware Cloud director, vRealize Operations manager Tenant App, Usage Meter and Rabbit MQ.
Starting with version 1.2, VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager is delivered as a virtual appliance. You must deploy the virtual appliance on an ESXi host or in a vCenter Server.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-certificate-management-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-certificate-management-2/</guid><description>Manage VMware Cloud provider Lifecycle Manager Certificates # Configure VMware Cloud provider API and UI certificates.
VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager API Certificate Management
After deploying the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager appliance, VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager generates a self-signed certificates for the API and the internally used vault.
You can configure VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager to either use the self-signed certificate or your own custom certificate by providing a PKCS12 keystore containing the certificate.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-configuration/</guid><description>Product Repository # During the first boot of a newly deployed VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager appliance, the system automatically creates the product directories and sets their permissions. You can either upload the product binaries to the respective directories or mount an existing pre-configured repository directory. On VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager, you must store the product deployment and upgrade files in the respective product directories.
Upload the Product OVA Files to the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager Appliance # You must upload the product OVA files and product update files to a specific pre-defined file structure.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-deployment-subpage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-deployment-subpage/</guid><description>Deploy VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # Begin implementation of this solution by deploying VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager
Prerequisites # Verify that your environment fulfils the prerequisites for the deployment of VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager &amp;lt;&amp;lt;Link to overall Prerequisites.xls&amp;gt;&amp;gt;
Procedure # Configure Product Binaries for VMware Cloud provider Lifecycle Manager
The binaries (ova files) for deploying the supported products must be downloaded and provided to the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager application.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cplcm-deployment/</guid><description>Implementation of VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # Implementation of VMware Cloud provider Lifecycle Manager(cplcm) includes deployment of the necessary components like VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager Appliance, NFS share for storing product binaries in VMware Cloud Foundation for automated deployment of products like VMware Cloud Director, Usage Meter, vRealize Operations Tenant App and RabbitQ
For information on the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager design, refer to the Detailed design of VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager section.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/nsx-t-dc-register/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/nsx-t-dc-register/</guid><description>Register NSX-T Datacenter # To enable VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager to manage products, first, you must register a datacenter component.
The datacenter components are instances or services available in the datacenter that VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager does not manage. You can register vCenter Server, NSX-T, and vRealize Operations Manager as datacenter components.
Register NSX-T # API Procedure
Download &amp;amp; import Postman collection Read More</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/rabbitmq-deployment-subpage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/rabbitmq-deployment-subpage/</guid><description>Deployment of RabbitMQ using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # Usage Meter to be deployed through GUI of VMware Cloud provider Lifecycle Manager.
Begin implementation of this solution by deploying VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager
Prerequisites # You must meet all requirements before deploying Usage Meter. For information, see Before you deploy RabbitMQ. Verify that the RabbitMQ version you want to deploy is supported by VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/rabbitmq-deployment-using-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/rabbitmq-deployment-using-api/</guid><description>Deploy RabbitMQ using API # Execute the respective API call from the postman Collection after changing the environment variables and parameters.
API Procedure # To deploy one or several products, a Lifecycle Manager environment must be created. An environment can be created using the below POST request.
Method: POST
URL: /api/{apiVersion}/lcm/environment?action=DEPLOY
Header: name: JSESSIONID – value: a valid jsessionid
Sample bodies # Deploy RabbitMQ - API call at a high level # Define Environment Name and ID</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/rabbitmq-deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/rabbitmq-deployment/</guid><description>Implementation of RabbitMQ using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # Implementation of RabbitMQ includes deployment of VMware Cloud Director on VMware Cloud Foundation using UI of VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager
For information on the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager design, refer to the Detailed design of RabbitMQ section.
Prerequisites # Verify that your environment is configured according to Before You Apply This Guidance and the Planning and Preparation of RabbitMQ section.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/usagemeter-deployment-subpage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/usagemeter-deployment-subpage/</guid><description>Deployment of Usage Meter using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # Usage Meter to be deployed through GUI of VMware Cloud provider Lifecycle Manager.
Begin implementation of this solution by deploying VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager
Prerequisites # You must meet all requirements before deploying Usage Meter. For information, see Before you deploy Usage Meter. Verify that the Usage Meter version you want to deploy is supported by VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/usagemeter-deployment-using-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/usagemeter-deployment-using-api/</guid><description>Deploy Usage Meter using API # Execute the respective API call from the postman Collection after changing the environment variables and parameters.
API Procedure # Usage Meter can be deployed as well using an API call, sample postman collection can be referred for the deployment.
However, the product documentation needs to be followed for successful deployment.
To deploy one or several products, a Lifecycle Manager environment must be created.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/usagemeter-deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/usagemeter-deployment/</guid><description>Deployment of Usage Meter using the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # The deployment of Usage Meter is part of the deployment of VMware Cloud Director on VMware Cloud Foundation using the GUI of VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager. For information on the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager design, refer to the Detailed design of Usage Meter section.
Prerequisites # Verify that your environment is configured according to Before You Apply This Guidance and the Planning and Preparation of Usage Meter section.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vc-dc-register/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vc-dc-register/</guid><description>Register Datacenter # To enable VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager to manage products, first, you must register a datacenter component.
The datacenter components are instances or services available in the datacenter that VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager does not manage. You can register vCenter Server, NSX-T, and vRealize Operations Manager as datacenter components.
Register a Datacenter Component # Using th below steps you can register vCenter, NSX-T or vROPS as a datacenter Component.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcd-deploy-subpage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcd-deploy-subpage/</guid><description>Deployment of VMware Cloud Director using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # Multi-node VMware Cloud Director to be deployed using GUI of VMware Cloud provider Lifecycle Manager
Begin implementation of this solution by deploying VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager
Prerequisites # You must meet all requirements for deployment of VMware Cloud Director. For information, see Before you deploy VMware Cloud Director.. Verify that VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager supports the VMware Cloud Director version you want to deploy.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcd-deployment-using-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcd-deployment-using-api/</guid><description>Deploy VMware Cloud Director using API # Execute the respective API call from the postman Collection after changing the environment variables and parameters.
API Procedure # To deploy one or several products, a Lifecycle Manager environment must be created. An environment can be created using the below POST request.
Method: POST
URL: /api/{apiVersion}/lcm/environment?action=DEPLOY
Header: name: JSESSIONID – value: a valid jsessionid
Sample bodies # Deploy VMware Cloud Director - API call at a high level # Define Environment Name and ID</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcd-deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vcd-deployment/</guid><description>Implementation of VMware Cloud Director using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # Implementation of VMware Cloud Director(VCD) includes deployment of VMware Cloud Director on VMware Cloud Foundation using GUI of VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager
For information on the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager design, refer to the Detailed design of VMware Cloud Director section.
Prerequisites # Verify that your environment is configured according to Before You Apply This Guidance and the Planning and Preparation of VMware Cloud Director section.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vrops-dc-register/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vrops-dc-register/</guid><description>Register Datacenter vRealize Operations Manager # To enable VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager to manage products, first, you must register a datacenter component.
The datacenter components are instances or services available in the datacenter that VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager does not manage. You can register vCenter Server, NSX-T, and vRealize Operations Manager as datacenter components.
Register vROPS # API Procedure
Download &amp;amp; import Postman collection Read More</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vrops-ta-deployment-subpage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vrops-ta-deployment-subpage/</guid><description>Deployment of Chargeback using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # Multi-node Chargeback (formerly vROPS Tenant App) to be deployed using GUI of VMware Cloud provider Lifecycle Manager
Begin implementation of this solution by deploying VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager
Prerequisites # You must meet all requirements before deploying vRealize Operations Manager Tenant App. For information, see Before you deploy vRealize Operations Manager Tenant App. Verify that the vRealize Operations Manager Tenant App version you want to deploy is supported by VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vropsta-deployment-using-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vropsta-deployment-using-api/</guid><description>Deploy vRealize Operations Tenant App using API # Execute the respective API call from the postman Collection after changing the environment variables and parameters.
API Procedure # vRealize Operations Tenant App can be deployed as well using an API call, sample postman collection can be referred for the deployment.
However, the product documentation needs to be followed for successful deployment.
To deploy one or several products, a Lifecycle Manager environment must be created.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vropsta-deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/vropsta-deployment/</guid><description>Implementation of vRealize Operations Tenant App using VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager # Implementation of vRealize Operations Tenant App includes deployment of VMware Cloud Director on VMware Cloud Foundation using GUI of VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager
For information on the VMware Cloud Provider Lifecycle Manager design, refer to the Detailed design of vRealize Operations Tenant App section.
Prerequisites # Verify that your environment is configured according to Before You Apply This Guidance and the Planning and Preparation of Usage Meter section.</description></item></channel></rss>