<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Infrastructure on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Infrastructure on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Planning and Preparation</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/planning/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Planning and Preparation # Coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Design</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/design/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Design # Coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Implementation</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/implementation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/implementation/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Implementation # Welcome!
Configuring VMware Cloud Director service for SDDC Endpoints # The following sections describes how to configure various SDDC endpoints for VMware Cloud Director service.
Configuring VMware Cloud Director service for VMware Cloud on AWS # See the instructions below on how to deploy VMware Cloud on AWS (VMConAWS) for multi-tenancy with VMware Cloud Director service.
VMware Cloud Director Service for VMware Cloud on AWS Deployment Guide</description></item><item><title>Cloud Infrastructure Operations</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/operations/</guid><description>Cloud Infrastructure Operations # vCenter Server Metering # Usage Meter collects product usage information from all vCenter servers that are registered with Usage Meter.
Note: Usage Meter does not traverse Enhanced Linked Mode, and it requires registering all vCenter servers, part of this mode, to meter their usage data.
VMware Cloud Provider Program partners should utilize VCPP licenses for all servers used in the service delivery path or administration control plane.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Director Service for Google Cloud VMware Engine Deployment Guide</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cds-gcve-deployment-guide-msp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cds-gcve-deployment-guide-msp/</guid><description>Introduction # This white paper is intended for VCPP Cloud Providers who need guidance on how to configure Google Cloud VMware Engine with VMware Cloud Director service (CDs). The content below describes the manual deployment process required to setup the Google Cloud projects, configure them, deploy a Software Defined Data Center (SDDC), associate it to CDs, and the process to configure a virtual private network (VPN) solution for connectivity to isolated networks.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Director Service for VMware Cloud on AWS Deployment Guide</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cds-vmc-deployment-guide-msp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-infrastructure/cds-vmc-deployment-guide-msp/</guid><description>VMware Cloud Director Service for VMware Cloud on AWS Deployment Guide # VMware Cloud Director™ service enables cloud providers to use VMware Cloud on AWS in multi-tenant modality with enhanced VMware NSX-T support, allowing provisioning of custom-sized, tenant-based, isolated, and secure VMware Cloud resources. This ability to service multiple smaller and medium sized tenants on the same infrastructure, offers flexibility to right-size the VMware Cloud on AWS environments to meet customer needs and requirements of all customer tiers.</description></item></channel></rss>