<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware Cloud Director service on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-director-service/</link><description>Recent content in VMware Cloud Director service on VMware Cloud Provider Architecture Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-director-service/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware Cloud Director Service for Google Cloud VMware Engine Deployment Guide</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-director-service/cds-gcve-deployment-guide-msp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-director-service/cds-gcve-deployment-guide-msp/</guid><description>Introduction # This white paper is intended for VCPP Cloud Providers who need guidance on how to configure Google Cloud VMware Engine with VMware Cloud Director service (CDs). The content below describes the manual deployment process required to setup the Google Cloud projects, configure them, deploy a Software Defined Data Center (SDDC), associate it to CDs, and the process to configure a virtual private network (VPN) solution for connectivity to isolated networks.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Director Service for VMware Cloud on AWS Deployment Guide</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-director-service/cds-vmc-deployment-guide-msp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-director-service/cds-vmc-deployment-guide-msp/</guid><description>VMware Cloud Director Service for VMware Cloud on AWS Deployment Guide # VMware Cloud Director™ service enables cloud providers to use VMware Cloud on AWS in multi-tenant modality with enhanced VMware NSX-T support, allowing provisioning of custom-sized, tenant-based, isolated, and secure VMware Cloud resources. This ability to service multiple smaller and medium sized tenants on the same infrastructure, offers flexibility to right-size the VMware Cloud on AWS environments to meet customer needs and requirements of all customer tiers.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Director service Implementation</title><link>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-director-service/implementation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcpat.cloudhappens.io/docs/cloud-director-service/implementation/</guid><description>VMware Cloud Director service Implementation # This guidance provides a prescriptive path for deploying VMware Cloud Director service and software defined datacenters (SDDCs) as endpoints to consume for tenant workloads. This provides for an asset light model based on VMware stack deployments on public hyperscalers.
Prerequisites # You must first have access to the VMware Cloud Services portal (CSP), for more information see VMware Cloud Services Documentation. You should have an existing VMware Cloud Director services instance to manage the SDDC endpoint you wish to deploy, for more information see What is VMware Cloud Director service and How Does it Work.</description></item></channel></rss>